**Privacy Policy**

Effective Date: July 1, 2024

This policy discloses the privacy practices of WeatherBug properties (referred to as "we," "us," "our," "WeatherBug"). These include the website [https://www.weatherbug.com](https://www.weatherbug.com/), and the WeatherBug desktop and mobile applications (collectively, "the Services"). This privacy policy describes how WeatherBug collects, uses, shares, and secures the personal information you provide. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use, access and correction of your personal information. WeatherBug is a division of xAd, Inc. dba GroundTruth ("GroundTruth"). To learn more about GroundTruth and its privacy practices, please visit [https://www.groundtruth.com/privacy-policy](https://www.groundtruth.com/privacy-policy).  
  
WeatherBug's Privacy Policy, below, describes the types of personal data WeatherBug collects, the types of third parties to which it discloses personal data, and the purposes for which it does so. For information on opting out of interest-based advertising delivered on WeatherBug Services, please see the Digital Advertising & Your Choices section of this Policy below.  

**Information Collection**  
We collect the following types of information:  
  
**Personal information** refers to information that identifies specifically who you are, such as your name, e-mail address, or mailing address. We may also ask you for demographic information or other information such as ZIP Code, gender, date of birth and your interests. In many cases we need this information to provide the personalized or enhanced service that you have requested. You may provide us with this personal information if you register with WeatherBug, for a personalized service, submit pictures, video or other user generated content, or participate in a promotion or sweepstakes. We or our affiliates may also derive physical address information and infer other general or precise location-related information from the information collected from mobile devices, such as the stores and other places the device frequents, or usage information for differentiating and/or associating multiple device users as well as associating devices or users with locations such as a household or workplace.  
  
**Usage information** refers to information that we collect about browsers, wireless networks and devices that access our Services. For instance, we may collect information about how many users come to our Services, what types of browsers and devices accessed the Services, IP address, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, the files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date/time stamp, clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site, device platform ad ID, date and time of visit, web viewing and app use data, wireless network performance, usage and identifiers, and precise location data. We may use cookies, web beacons, a device identifier, and other similar technology to collect this type of usage data. For more information, please see the "Tracking Technologies" section below. This data may be collected from our desktop properties or mobile apps even when you are not actively using the app.  
  
We may also collect data from certain third parties and combine that data with information we collect as described above or derive through analytical techniques, including combining personal and usage information together.  
  
**Location Information**  
When you have installed or use a WeatherBug service, such as one of our mobile applications, we may collect information about your device's precise location, including your location relative to and within third party merchant locations (in-store beacons). We may also collect data from cellular towers or WiFi networks near a device to infer the location of a device. Our affiliates including GroundTruth may also share location related-information with us. We may collect or receive location-related information even if you are not logged into or using the application.  
  
We use location information to operate and enhance our service as well as customize the content, weather alerts, and advertising we provide to you. We may also share location information with our affiliates including GroundTruth to enable product features and for advertising and reporting purposes. Visit the [Digital Advertising & Your Choices section](#digitaladvertisingandyourchoices) to learn how to control the collection and use of location information.  
  
**Tracking Technologies**  
WeatherBug and our partners, affiliates, analytics, or service providers use cookies, beacons, tags, scripts, device identifiers, or similar technologies to analyze trends and use of our Services, administer the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on a user-level and aggregated basis. You can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level, but if you choose to disable cookies, it may limit your use of certain features or functions on our Website or service. To manage Flash cookies, please click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). To learn more about the use of such data collected through these technologies, visit the [Digital Advertising & Your Choices section](#digitaladvertisingandyourchoices).  
  
**Use of Information**  
We may use the information we collect or derive through analytical techniques for a variety of purposes, including:

* Operating, maintaining, customizing, and improving our Services;
* Responding to your requests and questions;
* Providing personalized weather information;
* Delivering advertising we believe to be relevant to your interests, both about our products and the products of other third parties - for instance, we may use the location related data to present ads from a local business or use that and other data we collect to deliver ads that you may find more relevant;
* Performing analytics, research, and attribution, including predicting possible relationships among different browsers and devices;
* Monitoring the Services for compliance with the law and our terms of service;
* For product development; and
* Any other purpose disclosed at the time of collection.

**Information Sharing**  
We may share information we collect or derive through analytical techniques with third parties for a variety of purposes, including:

* With our affiliates and with other divisions of GroundTruth for their own use;
* With service providers that help provide the Services pursuant to our instructions, such as ad serving;
* With third parties for their own direct marketing or targeted advertising purposes;
* With wireless service providers and other third parties who use it to analyze consumer mobile trends and analyze and improve wireless networks;
* For analytics and research purposes;
* As part of a corporate sale, merger, or acquisition, or other transfer of all or part of our assets including at bankruptcy;
* In response to a court order, warrant, subpoena, or other legal process, or as otherwise required by law or to meet national security requirements, or when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the rights of third parties, investigate fraud, or respond to government request; or
* With your consent.

Also, when you share information through our Services, such as photos or videos, some information about you may be made available to the public. If you would like us to remove your post from the page or application, contact us at [privacy@weatherbug.com](mailto:privacy@weatherbug.com).  
  
**Digital Advertising & Your Choices**We may partner with GroundTruth and with various third parties that engage in interest-based advertising ("IBA"). This type of advertising involves the collection of web viewing, location-related information and mobile application use data from our Services and other non-affiliated websites and mobile applications over time and across associated devices. This data is used to infer interests and deliver relevant advertising back to a browser or device, and to browsers and devices that are associated with each other. WeatherBug adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (“DAA”) self-regulatory principles.  Browser Choice: For more information about IBA, and to learn how you can exercise choice regarding the practice on your browser for companies that participate in the DAA WebChoices tool, you can visit [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) or TrustArc ([click here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/)).  
App Choice: You may also download an application on your iOS or Android device in order to exercise choice regarding the collection of mobile application use activity for IBA on this device by companies that participate in those choice tools. Links to those applications are below:  
  
Location Data Choice: The DAA's AppChoices tool can also be used to exercise choice regarding the collection and use of precise location data by GroundTruth for IBA purposes. To limit the collection of precise location data by other parties through our application for a particular device, you can turn location services off through your device's settings.  
  
Note that electing to opt out from IBA will not stop advertising from appearing in your browser or applications. It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests. In addition, note that if you use a different browser or device, erase cookies from your browser, or reset your platform ad identifier, you may need to renew your opt-out choice. In addition, companies may still collect data in browsers or apps for non-IBA purposes such as for analytics and reporting purposes, operations, improving our or their Services, and frequency capping.  
  
For more information regarding the partners with whom we may share your data for uses other than the provision of our services or advertising purposes, [click here](https://www.weatherbug.com/partners).  
  
**WeatherBug Mobile Application**When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier.  
  
We may send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. To ensure you receive proper notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device for example the operating system type or user identification information.  
  
We use mobile analytics to allow us to better understand the functionality of our application on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from.  
  
We use Google Analytics to better understand how visitors interact with our Websites. This service provides usage information including but not limited to data on where visitors came from, what actions they took on our Sites, and where visitors went when they left our Sites. We use this information to improve your experience when visiting our Website. Please click [here](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners) to learn more about this service and how to opt out of data collection by Google Analytics.  
  
**Links or Access to Third Party Sites and Services**  
Our Services include links or offer access to other websites or services whose privacy practices may differ from those of WeatherBug. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website or services you visit or access.  
  
**Access to Personal Information**  
Upon request, WeatherBug will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You can correct factual errors in your personal information by sending us a request that explains the error. If you wish to access, update, or correct your personal information that we collect online, please contact us by mail at the address shown in the Contact Us section below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.  
  
**Data Retention**  
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active, as needed to provide you services, or for so long as we have a legitimate business purpose for retaining it, or as otherwise required by applicable law. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements.  
  
**Information from Children**  
We do not knowingly request or collect personal information from anyone under the age of 13.  
  
**Information Security**  
We take reasonable steps to help maintain the information we collect in a secure manner and we follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at [privacy@weatherbug.com](mailto:privacy@weatherbug.com).

**U.S. State  Privacy Rights** This section contains disclosures required by the laws in California, Colorado, Connecticut, Florida, Montana, Nevada, Oregon, Texas, Utah, and Virginia (“Certain States”).  If you are a resident of such states, this section of the Privacy Policy contains disclosures required by law and explains rights that may be available to you. Our use of the terms “sell” and “share” below generally refers to these California definitions. Consumers with disabilities may access this notice by utilizing standard screen readers.  
  
**Personal Information We Collect, Process, Disclose, and Sell/Share**  
We collect the categories of personal information identified in the chart below. As further set forth in the chart below we have disclosed and sold or shared personal information about Certain State residents to third parties for business or commercial purposes.

|     |     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **Categories of Personal Information** | **Categories of sources from which information is collected:** | **Business or commercial purposes for collection, use, and sharing:** | **Disclosed for business purposes to the following categories of third parties:** | **Sold to or shared with the following categories of third parties:** |
| Personal identifiers (such as first and last name, email address) | Consumers | Marketing;  <br>  <br>Auditing;  <br>Legal compliance;  <br>Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  <br>Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  <br>and  <br>Other one-time uses. | This information is not disclosed to third parties in the past 12 months. | This information was not sold in the past 12 months to third parties |
| Online identifiers (such as unique online identifiers) | Consumers and  <br>Other third party partners | Advertising;<br><br>Targeted advertising;  <br>Marketing;  <br>Data analytics and insights;  <br>Reporting and fraud prevention;  <br>Auditing;  <br>Legal compliance;  <br>Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  <br>Debugging;  <br>Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  <br>Internal research for technological improvement;  <br>Internal operations;  <br>Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  <br>Other one-time uses. | Service Providers | Other third party partners |
| Demographic information (such as gender) | Consumers | Advertising services and advertising products; Targeted advertising;  <br>Data analytics and insights;  <br>Reporting and fraud prevention;  <br>Legal compliance;  <br>Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  <br>Debugging;  <br>Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  <br>Internal research for technological improvement;  <br>Internal operations;  <br>Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  <br>Other one-time uses. | Service Providers | This information was not sold in the past 12 months to third parties. |
| Internet or other electronic network activity information (such as browsing history, search history, interactions with a website, email, application, or advertisement) | Consumers and<br><br>Service providers; | Advertising services and advertising products; Targeted advertising;  <br>Data analytics and insights;<br><br>Measurement;  <br>Attribution;  <br>Reporting and fraud prevention;  <br>Legal compliance;  <br>Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  <br>Debugging;  <br>Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  <br>Internal research for technological improvement;  <br>Internal operations;  <br>Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  <br>Other one-time uses. | Service Providers | Companies for which we provide advertising services. |
| Geolocation information | Consumers. | Advertising services and advertising products; Targeted advertising;  <br>Data analytics and insights;<br><br>Measurement;  <br>Attribution;  <br>Reporting and fraud prevention;  <br>Legal compliance;  <br>Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  <br>Debugging;  <br>Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  <br>Internal research for technological improvement;  <br>Internal operations;  <br>Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  <br>Other one-time uses. | Service Providers | Other third party partners |
| Inferences drawn from the above information about your predicted characteristics and preferences | Other third party partners | Advertising services and advertising products; Targeted advertising;  Data analytics and insights;<br><br>Measurement;  <br>Attribution;  <br>Reporting and fraud prevention;  <br>Legal compliance;  <br>Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  <br>Debugging;  <br>Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  <br>Internal research for technological improvement;  <br>Internal operations;  <br>Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  <br>Other one-time uses. | This information is not disclosed to third parties in the past 12 months. | This information was not disclosed to third parties in the past 12 months. |
| Other information about you that is linked to the personal information above | Consumers; | Advertising services and advertising products; Targeted advertising;  Data analytics and insights;<br><br>Measurement;  <br>Attribution;  <br>Reporting and fraud prevention;  <br>Legal compliance;  <br>Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;  <br>Debugging;  <br>Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments;  <br>Internal research for technological improvement;  <br>Internal operations;  <br>Activities to develop, maintain and improve our products and services; and  <br>Other one-time uses. | Service Providers | Other third party partners |
| Employee and job applicant data, which may include the categories of personal information listed above that are collected during the job application process and while individuals are WeatherBug employees | Consumers; service providers; and other third party partners | Processing your application.<br><br>Using your information in connection with your employment roles and responsibilities.  This includes, for example:<br><br>·          Providing you with services and tools to use in connection with your employment, such as email service and information technologies;<br><br>·          Responding to your requests;<br><br>·          Maintaining compliance with our policies and procedures;<br><br>·          Paying you and administering your employment benefits, including those provided to other individuals like family members; and<br><br>·          Responding to emergencies or safety concerns, such as by maintaining and using your emergency contact information.<br><br>Other business purposes as identified in the CCPA, which include:<br><br>·          Auditing related to our interactions with you;<br><br>·          Legal compliance;<br><br>·          Detecting and protecting against security incidents, fraud, and illegal activity;<br><br>·          Debugging;<br><br>·          Performing services (for us or our service provider) such as account servicing, processing orders and payments, and analytics;<br><br>·          Internal research for technological improvement;<br><br>·          Internal operations;<br><br>·          Activities to maintain and improve our business; and<br><br>·          Other one-time uses. | Service providers | This information was not sold in the past 12 months to third parties |

NOTICE: We may sell your sensitive personal data.  

We may share information that has been de-identified or aggregated without limitation.

We may use and share aggregated and deidentified information to the extent permitted by applicable law.  When we use deidentified information, we maintain and use the information in deidentified form and do not attempt to reidentify it, except to check whether our deidentification processes satisfy the requirements of applicable law.

**Information Retention.**  We will retain each category of personal information we collect in accordance with applicable laws and as reasonably necessary for our processing purposes set out under this Privacy Policy.

**Rights Regarding Personal Information.**  Residents of Certain States have certain rights with respect to the personal information collected by us. If you are a resident or Certain States, you may be able to exercise the following rights where applicable regarding personal information, subject to certain exceptions and limitations contained in the relevant state law:

* The right to confirm whether we process personal information about you.
* The right to correct inaccuracies in the personal information we have collected about you.
* The right to know the categories and specific pieces of personal information we collect, use, disclose, and sell about you, the categories of sources from which we collected personal information, our purposes for collecting or selling your personal information, the categories of your personal information that we have either sold or disclosed for a business purpose, and the categories of third parties with which we have shared personal information;
* The right to request that we delete the personal information we have collected from you or maintain about you.

·       The right to opt out of (i) the sharing of personal information for targeted advertising or (ii) the sale of personal information.  Please note that if you opt out of certain types of sales, we may be unable to provide you with the services that rely on such sales. Additionally, we do not knowingly sell or share personal data of individuals under 16.

·       Depending on your state, the right to receive a portable and readily usable copy of the personal information we have collected about you, to the extent feasible.

·       **Choice Regarding Sensitive Information.** We may use or disclose the sensitive information that we collect from you for purposes that require an opt-out opportunity under the law.  Depending on your state, you may have the right to:

•       Limit our use or disclosure of certain “sensitive” personal information about you;

•       Opt out of our processing of certain “sensitive” personal information; or

•       Withdraw consent for such processing if you previously gave it.

* The right not to receive discriminatory treatment for the exercise of these privacy rights.

To exercise any of the above rights, please contact us using the following information and submit the required verifying information, as further described below:

* Via email at [privacyrights@weatherbug.com](mailto: privacyrights@weatherbug.com)
* To exercise the right to opt out and/or limit sensitive data processing, online at  [https://www.weatherbug.com/privacyfeedback](https://www.weatherbug.com/privacyfeedback).  We may use and disclose sensitive personal information for the purposes described above, including for advertising.
* You can also exercise your right to opt out of the sale/sharing of your personal information, and/or limit sensitive data processing: (i) automatically through the WeatherBug mobile application by opening the application in one of the Certain States, clicking on the menu icon in top left corner, clicking on the About/Privacy link, clicking the State Privacy Rights link from the About/Privacy page, and then selecting the right(s) you would like to exercise; and (ii) automatically through the WeatherBug website by opening the website in one of the Certain States, and then clicking on the applicable link located at the bottom of the website for the right(s) you would like to exercise. Please note, this feature is only available in versions 5.51 and later of the WeatherBug mobile application.

In the event you are a user of the WeatherBug application, in order to exercise any of the above rights, you will need to provide your AppInstance identifier.  To access your AppInstance identifier, open the WeatherBug application on your device, click the menu icon in top left corner and select “Send Feedback” from the menu. The AppInstance identifier is included with the list of information provided here.

You may designate an authorized agent to make a request on your behalf, and either you or the agent must provide this permission to WeatherBug. To do so you will need to provide the agent with signed written permission to act on your behalf.

For Colorado, Connecticut, Montana, Oregon, Texas and Virginia residents, if you have submitted a request that you feel we have not reasonably fulfilled, you may contact us to appeal our decision by sending an email to [privacyrightsappeals@weatherbug.com](mailto:privacyrightsappeals@weatherbug.com).

Further, Oregon residents may exercise the right to obtain a list of the third parties to which we have disclosed personal information, in the manner set forth above.

**Universal opt-out mechanisms (“UOOMs”):** Under some applicable state laws, certain mechanisms or technologies may be used to signal your opt-out preferences to entities that process personal data. To the extent that we are able to recognize signals from these UOOMs and they are legally sufficient, we will process these signals as requests to opt out of sales or processing for the purposes of targeted advertising. Depending on the UOOM you select, the opt-out may apply only to certain interactions, such as a specific browser or device. You may select and install a UOOM of your preference per the provider’s instructions.

In the previous calendar year, WeatherBug: 

·         Received 20 request to delete, complied in whole or in part with 20 of them, and denied 0 of them.

·         Received 500 request to opt out of data sale, complied in whole or in part with 500 of them, and denied 0 of them.

The median number of days within which WeatherBug substantively responded to California consumers’ requests to know, requests to delete, and requests to opt out in the previous calendar year is 1 day.

**European Privacy Rights**

This section only applies to individuals that use our Services from the European Economic Area (“EEA”), the United Kingdom, and Switzerland.

We process personal information to fulfill a contract to which you are a party, such as when you download the WeatherBug app and accept its Terms of Use.  We may also process personal information pursuant to your consent, such as when you voluntarily provide personal information to WeatherBug to customize your services. You have the right to withdraw consent at any time.  To exercise this right, contact us at [WB-Privacy-EU@weatherbug.com](mailto:WB-Privacy-EU@weatherbug.com).  

We also may process your personal data when it is in our legitimate interests to do so and when these interests are not overridden by your rights.  Our legitimate interests include processing personal data for: direct marketing; preventing fraud; sharing data among subsidiaries for internal purposes; ensuring network and information security; reporting criminal acts or threats to public security; establishing legally binding agreements with third parties; billing third parties; and taking internal measures to improve the functionality of the Services.

On other occasions, we process personal information where required by law.  We may also process personal information if necessary to protect your interests or the interests of a third party.

You have a right to the following:

·         To request access to the personal information we hold about you;

·         To request that we rectify or erase personal information about you;

·         To request that we restrict or block the processing of your personal information;

·         Under certain circumstances, to receive personal information about you that we store and transmit to another with hindrance from us, including that we provide your personal information directly to another, i.e., a right to data portability; and

·         Where we previously obtained your consent, to withdraw consent to processing your personal information.

To exercise these rights, please contact us at [WB-Privacy-EU@weatherbug.com](mailto:WB-Privacy-EU@weatherbug.com).  Please be aware that we may be unable to afford these rights to you under certain circumstances, such as if we are legally prevented from doing so.  Additionally, you have the right to lodge a complaint against us.  To do so, contact the supervisory authority in your country of residence.

We will process and store your information only for the period necessary to achieve the purpose of the storage, or as permitted by law.  The criteria used to determine the period of storage of information is the respective statutory retention period.  After expiration of that period, the corresponding information is routinely deleted, as long as it is no longer necessary for the fulfillment of a contract or the initiation of a contract.

The personal information you provide to WeatherBug is stored on servers in the US and supported from the US. We also transfer personal information about you (whether collected online or offline) to our legal entities and affiliates and to service providers who perform functions on our behalf which are based around the world including in countries outside of the EEA, UK, and Switzerland and this information may be stored and processed in those countries which may have different data protection standards to those which apply in your country of residence.  
  
**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect the changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes with respect to how we treat your personal information we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.  
  
**Contact Us**  
For any questions about this privacy policy you may contact us at:  
xAd, Inc. dba GroundTruth (WeatherBug)  
Global Headquarters  
One World Trade Center  
60th Floor  
New York, NY 10007  

Visitors from the European Economic Area, Switzerland, and the United Kingdom may contact our Data Protection Officer, Christopher Yamaoka, at DPO@groundtruth.com.
